FAVOUR ONUOHA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Senior Software Developer at Eganow and also a content creator

I am self-taught and I love talking & writing about Web3, web development, & software development in general.

I have been coding for over 8 years and am currently a Backend Fintech Engineer with experience in working with Core Banking Services with extensive knowledge of building USSD (short codes) and working on mobile money frameworks having integrated and worked with teams from the major Telecos in Ghana.

My favorite programming languages are JavaScript, Python, Java, and C# and I use a variety of frameworks like Django, React, Node JS, Express JS, ASP.NET Core, and Angular.

I am on a journey to make Web3 knowledge accessible to everyone.

WORK HISTORY

Community Lead, 01/2022 to Current

Showwcase - San Francisco, United States

- Building Communities around Web3, Blockhain Dev, NFTs and Web Development.
- Making Showwcase the goto professional place for developers.

Technical Writer, 12/2021 to Current

Hashnode - Deleware, United States

- Wrote high engaging Web3 content to help bridge the knowledge gap between Web2 and Web3.
- Researched topics from reliable sources to produce high-quality and accurate content.
- Oversimplify topics and explained them in more easy ways that boosted readership

Senior Software Engineer, 01/2021 to Current

Teksol Eganow - Accra, Ghana

- Integrated and worked with teams from the largest Mobile Money
 Telcos in Ghana to implement Cashless Transactions for eganow to
 offer cashless payments to our customers and clients.
- Create a Short Code System to increase our clients service accessibility.
- Created high performance API services for our Core Banking Solutions to enable their customers to make cashless transactions with their

CONTACT

Address: Accra, Greate Accra 00233

Phone: 233543767156

Email: favouronu@gmail.com

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO, PROFILES

- · https://me.heyonuoha.live
- https://blog.heyonuoha.live
- https://www.linkedin.com /in/heyonuoha/

SKILLS

- HTMI
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React
- Vue JS
- web3.js/ethers.js/web3.py
- Solidity
- Hardhat
- Truffle
- Node IS
- · C#/ASP.NET Core
- Python/Django/Flask
- Content Creation
- · Growth Hacking
- · Audience Building

mobile phones.

Senior Software Engineer, 07/2018 to Current

TekSol LTD - Accra, Ghana

- Started my career and tested my skills by solving problems in multiple programming languages.
- Developed large scale frontend application for our banking clients to make their customer management easier.
- Created mobile apps to enable our customers reach a larger audience.

EDUCATION

No Degree, Software Engineering

NIIT - Accra, Ghana

High School Diploma

Wesley Grammar Senior High School - Accra, Ghana